Guide to the Robert Fridenberg Collection of Portrait and Topographical Prints
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Robert Fridenberg Collection of Portrait and Topographical Prints
1500-1945
1750-1900
GEN MSS 1000
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
121.3
(377 boxes)
A collection of European and American portrait and topographical prints that includes work by printmakers Samuel Arlent Edwards, George Edward Perine, Eugène Sadoux, and others.
Fridenberg, Robert
Bacle, César Hipólito, 1794-1838
Cheney, John, 1801-1885
Edwards, Samuel Arlent, 1861-1938
Edwin, David, 1776-1841
Gimbrede, Thomas, 1781-1832
Haines, William, 1778-1848
Hall, Charles Bryan, 1840-1913
Hollyer, Samuel, 1826-1919
Leney, William Satchwell, 1769-1831
Longacre, James Barton, 1794-1869
Orsay, Alfred Guillaume Gabriel, comte d', 1801-1852
Perine, George Edward, 1837-1885
Rosenthal, Albert, 1863-1939
Rosenthal, Max, 1833-1918
Scoles, John, 1772?-1853
Watson, Dawson Dawson, 1864-1939
Wright, James Osborne, 1851-1920
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Joseph Verner Reed (Yale 1926), 1958.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Portraits, 1500-1910. II. Topographical Views, 1750-1900. III. Book Illustrations. IV. Other Prints. V. Robert Fridenberg Administrative Records.
Robert Fridenberg Collection of Portrait and Topographical Prints
The Robert Fridenberg Collection of Portrait and Topographical Prints was purchased in New York by Joseph Verner Reed (1902-1973, Yale 1926) sometime after Fridenberg's death in 1946. Reed, a collector of fine prints, had been a patron of Fridenberg and his successor, Joseph A. Heckel. The prints were moved from New York into an outbuilding at Reed's home in Greenwich, Connecticut, where they remained for more than a decade. In 1957, at his wife's urging because she needed the outbuilding for a potting shed, Reed offered the collection to the Yale University Art Gallery, but finding the contents more historical than fine art, the museum declined. Reed's second offer, to the Yale University Library, was accepted by then-Yale University Librarian James T. Babb. Described in an April 3, 1958, list of "Important Recent Gifts" to the library, the "collection of prints and plates contained in eighty-nine cabinets, two sideboards, eighty-two cartons, and eighty packages" was move into the basement of Sterling Memorial Library. In his 1958 appraisal for Reed, Heckel stated that the collection held "over 500,000 Old Engravings" consisting of historical portraits and views, and English and American drama, that "took over 75 years to accumulate."
The collection remained in the basement until the early 1960s when the Yale library administration decided to bring the history of printing, fine printing, and graphic arts volumes together following models established in 1938 at Harvard University by founding curator Philip Hofer (1898-1984) at Houghton Library's Department of Printing and Graphic Arts, and in 1940 at Princeton University by the printer and typographic designer Elmer Adler (1884-1962) at Firestone Library's Graphic Arts Collection. Dale R. Roylance was hired away from Princeton's Graphic Arts Collection in 1960 as a reference specialist for graphic arts, and in April 1962 a new curatorial position was planned in order to support the library's goal of creating a special collection with a "selective, artistically qualitative approach to printing, illustrating, and book-making." Mentioned as cornerstones of the new Graphic Arts Collection were the collections of fine printing previously donated to Yale by Frank Altschul (1887-1981, Yale 1908) and John Hay Whitney (1904-1982, Yale 1928), and the "Reed prints"; they were to be joined by other materials combed from Sterling Memorial Library's general book stacks. Dale Roylance was made a full curator in 1965, and actively developed, exhibited, and published the collection until he returned to Princeton in 1979; Gay Walker followed him as curator, and served from 1979 until 1991. The collection itself was retitled the Arts of the Book Collection by April 1972 and thereafter was moved into a suite of rooms on the library's ground floor south of the High Street entrance.
At some point after 1987 the Fridenberg prints, then known as the "Vertical File Collection of Plates and Prints," were moved from Sterling's fourth floor to a room just outside Arts of the Book Collection. Partially organized and little used, most of the portrait prints had been rehoused by students in several (generally incomplete) campaigns, and were stored in file cabinets. Oversized prints remained housed inside labeled folders Fridenberg created from extra plates taken from broken folio volumes, primarily sets of the nine-volume Galeries Historiques du Palais de Versailles (Paris: Imprimerie Royale, 1839-1853). The small topographical prints were largely untouched and stayed as they had been in Fridenberg's shop, in geographic-based groupings held within repurposed and relabeled cases of disbound books.
On March 16, 1992, the prints were moved in their file cabinets to Yale's Lewis Walpole Library in Farmington, Connecticut, and placed in an outbuilding. Joan Sussler, curator of prints at the library, mined the collection for images relevant to the Walpole collection. Approximately half of the prints of England and Scotland, and a good selection of English portraits, were extracted and taken into the library's storage area but were not cataloged, processed, or integrated into the Lewis Walpole collection. In 1999 the "Prints and Plates Collection" was acquired by Beinecke Library, packed into cartons, and returned to New Haven; retitled the "General Print Collection," it was given the call number Uncat MS Vault Prints, and a box-level inventory was created without a catalog record in Orbis. In 2012 more refined processing began on the peripatetic collection, and it was once again retitled, this time to acknowledge Robert Fridenberg as its collector. In 2015 the British prints at the Lewis Walpole Library were transferred to Beinecke and added to the collection. Views of London and English towns were either interfiled with those already sorted and filed or added to the end of the existing topographical files. The portraits were left physically together and filed at the end of the topographical files; both were integrated intellectually through listings in the finding aid.
This collection history was compiled through telephone interviews with Joseph Verner Reed Jr. (1937-2016, Yale 1961, son of the donor), former Arts of the Book curators Dale Roylance (1924-2013) and Gay Walker, and former Yale Librarian James R. Tanis (1928-2015, Yale 1951, librarian 1965-1968), in addition to extensive research in the Yale Librarian Records (RU 120) at Manuscripts and Archives, Sterling Memorial Library.
Former call number: Uncat MS Vault Prints
Scope and Contents
A collection of European and American portrait and topographical prints that includes work by printmakers Samuel Arlent Edwards, George Edward Perine, Eugène Sadoux, and others.
Vanity fair (London, England: 1868); Caricatures and cartoons -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Collectors and collecting -- United States; Country homes -- Great Britain -- 18th century -- Pictorial works; Country homes -- Great Britain -- 19th century -- Pictorial works; Engravings (prints) -- France -- 18th century; Engravings (prints) -- France -- 19th century; Engravings (prints) -- Great Britain -- 18th century; Engravings (prints) -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Engravings (prints) -- United States -- 18th century; Engravings (prints) -- United States -- 19th century; Engravings (prints) -- United States -- 20th Century; Etchings (prints) -- United States -- 19th century; Mezzotints (prints) -- United States -- 19th century; Mezzotints (prints) -- United States -- 20th Century; Portrait prints -- France -- 18th century; Portrait prints -- France -- 19th century; Portrait prints -- Great Britain -- 18th century; Portrait prints -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Portrait prints -- United States -- 19th century; Portrait prints -- United States -- 20th Century; Steel engravings (visual works) -- United States -- 19th century; Stipple engravings (prints) -- Great Britain -- 18th century; Stipple engravings (prints) -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Stipple engravings (prints) -- United States -- 18th century; Stipple engravings (prints) -- United States -- 19th century; Topographical views -- 18th century; Topographical views -- 19th century; Topographical views -- France -- 18th century; Topographical views -- France -- 19th century; Topographical views -- Great Britain -- 18th century; Topographical views -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Woodburytypes (prints) -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Bacle, César Hipólito, 1794-1838; Bicknell, W. H. W. (William Harry Warren), 1860-1947; Cheney, John, 1801-1885; Edwards, Samuel Arlent, 1861-1938; Edwin, David, 1776-1841; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790 -- Portraits; Fridenberg, Robert; Gimbrede, Thomas, 1781-1832; Haines, William, 1778-1848; Hall, Charles Bryan, 1840-1913; Hollyer, Samuel, 1826-1919; Leney, William Satchwell, 1769-1831; Longacre, James Barton, 1794-1869; Orsay, Alfred Guillaume Gabriel, comte d', 1801-1852; Perine, George Edward, 1837-1885; Rosenthal, Albert, 1863-1939; Rosenthal, Max, 1833-1918; Sadoux, Eugène, 1841-1906; Scoles, John, 1772?-1853; Stuart, Frederick T., 1837-1913; Washington, George, 1732-1799 -- Portraits; Watson, Dawson Dawson, 1864-1939; Wright, James Osborne, 1851-1920; New York (N.Y.). Committee on Centennial Celebration of the Inauguration of Washington, 1789; Reed, Joseph Verner, 1902-1973 -- Ownership; Reed, Joseph Verner, 1902-1973
- Portraits, Series I
  Scope and Contents
  269 boxes
  Scenes of homes and incidents from life left filed with portraits. Spouses of people with folders are filed with them. In the Royal Figures section, with the exception of Marie Antoinette, consorts are filed with monarchs but not listed.
  - A
    - Aa - Anc general, 10 (Box 1, Folder 1-10)
    - And - Az general, 12 (Box 2, Folder 11-22)
    - Abercromby, Ralph, Sir, 1734-1801 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Abington, Frances Barton, 1737-1815 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - About, Edmond, 1828-1885 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Adams, John, 1735-1826 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Adams, Samuel, 1722-1803 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Addison, Joseph, 1672-1719 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Adolphus Frederick, Prince, Duke of Cambridge, 1774-1850 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Aguesseau, H. Fr. d' (Henri Francois), 1668-1751 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Aiguillon (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Aîné, Dupin, 1783-1865 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Ainsworth, William Harrison, 1805-1882 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Aitken, James, 1752-1777 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Akenside, Mark, 1721-1770 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Alba, Fernando Alvarez de Toledo, duque de, 1507-1582 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Alberoni, Giulio, 1664-1752 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Albert de Linge, Prince of Arenberg and Barbançon (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Alciati, Andrea, 1492-1550 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Alembert, Jean Le Rond d', 1717-1783 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Alfieri, Vittorio, 1749-1803 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Amboise, Georges d', 1460-1510 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Ames, Fisher, 1758-1808 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Amherst, Jeffery Amherst, Baron, 1717-1797 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Amyot, Jacques, 1513-1593 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - André, John, 1751-1780 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Andréossy, Antoine-Francois, comte, 1761-1828 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Andrewes, Lancelot, 1555-1626 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Anglesey, Henry William Paget, Marquis of, 1768-1854 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Angouleme, Charles de Valois, duc d', 1573-1650 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Angouleme, Louis Emmanuel de Valois, duc d' (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Anjou, François, duc d', 1554-1584 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Annandale, Charlotte Johnston, d. 1762 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Anson, George Anson, Baron, 1697-1762 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Anspach, Elizabeth, Margravine of, 1750-1828 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Aretino, Pietro, 1492-1556 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Argens, Jean-Baptiste de Boyer, marquis d', 1704-1771 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Argenson (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Argyll (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Ariosto, Lodovico, 1474-1533 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Arlington, Henry Bennet, Earl of, 1618-1685 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Arnold, Benedict, 1741-1801 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Arundel (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Arundel, Henry Frederick Howard, Earl of, 1608-1652 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Arundel, Thomas Howard, Earl of, 1585-1646 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Aubrey, John, 1626-1697 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Auchmuty, Samuel, Sir, 1756-1822 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Auckland, William Eden, Baron, 1744-1814 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Augereau, Pierre, 1757-1816 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Aumale, Henri d'Orléans, duc d', 1822-1897 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Avaux, Claude de Mesmes, comte d', 1595-1650 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Oversize
      - Aa - Arl general, 8 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 73-80)
      - Arm - Az general, 5 (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 81-85)
      - Abercromby - Anson, 27 (Box 8 (Oversize), Folder 86-112)
      - Arentino - Aumale, 14 (Box 9 (Oversize), Folder 113-126)
  - B
    - Ba - Baz general, 9 (Box 10, Folder 127-135)
    - Be - Bern general, 10 (Box 11, Folder 136-145)
    - Berr - Bog general, 10 (Box 12, Folder 146-155)
    - Boh - Brad general, 9 (Box 13, Folder 156-164)
    - Brag - Brue general, 9 (Box 14, Folder 165-173)
    - Bruh - Bz general, 8 (Box 15, Folder 174-181)
    - Baden (Box 16, Folder 182)
    - Baillie, Joanna, 1762-1851 (Box 16, Folder 183)
    - Bailly, Jean Sylvain, 1736-1793 (Box 16, Folder 184)
    - Balzac, Honoré de, 1799-1850 (Box 16, Folder 185)
    - Balzac, Jean-Louis Guez, seigneur de, 1597-1654 (Box 16, Folder 186)
    - Banks, Joseph, 1743-1820 (Box 16, Folder 187)
    - Barbaroux, Charles-Jean-Marie, 1767-1794 (Box 16, Folder 188)
    - Barbezieux, Louis Francois Marie, le Tellier, marquis de, 1668-1701 (Box 16)
    - Barère, B. (Bertrand), 1755-1841 (Box 16, Folder 189)
    - Baring, Francis, Sir, 1740-1810 (Box 16, Folder 190)
    - Barnave, Antoine, 1761-1793 (Box 16, Folder 191)
    - Bart, Jean, 1650-1702 (Box 16, Folder 192)
    - Barthelemy, Francois-Marie, marquis de, 1747-1830 (Box 16, Folder 193)
    - Barthélemy, J.-J. (Jean-Jacques), 1716-1795 (Box 16)
    - Bassompierre, François de, 1579-1646 (Box 16, Folder 194)
    - Batesius, Gulielmus (Box 16, Folder 195)
    - Baxter, Richard, 1615-1691 (Box 16, Folder 196)
    - Bayard, Pierre Terrail, seigneur de, ca. 1473-1524 (Box 16, Folder 197)
    - Bayle, Pierre, 1647-1706 (Box 16, Folder 198)
    - Bayly, Thomas Haynes, 1797-1839 (Box 16, Folder 199)
    - Beattie, James, 1735-1803 (Box 17, Folder 200)
    - Beauclerk, Diana, Lady, 1734-1808 (Box 17, Folder 201)
    - Beauharnais, Alexandre-François-Marie, vicomte de, 1760-1794 (Box 17, Folder 202)
    - Beauharnais, Eugène de, 1781-1824 (Box 17, Folder 203)
    - Beaumarchais, Pierre Augustin Caron de, 1732-1799 (Box 17, Folder 204)
    - Beaumont, Francis, 1584-1616 (Box 17, Folder 205)
    - Beckford, William, 1709-1770 (Box 17, Folder 206)
    - Beckford, William, 1760-1844 (Box 17, Folder 207)
    - Bedell, Gregory Thurston, 1817-1892 (Box 17, Folder 208)
    - Bedford (Box 17, Folder 209)
    - Bedford, Francis Russell, Earl of, 1593-1641 (Box 17, Folder 210)
    - Bedford, John Plantagenet, Duke of, 1389-1435 (Box 17, Folder 211)
    - Bedford, John Russell, Duke of, 1710-1771 (Box 17, Folder 212)
    - Bedford, William Russell, Duke of, and Anne Carre 1613-1700 (Box 17, Folder 213)
    - Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887 (Box 17, Folder 214)
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 17, Folder 215)
    - Belle-Isle (Box 17, Folder 216)
    - Bellièvre, Pomponne de, 1529-1607 (Box 17, Folder 217)
    - Belloy, M. de (Pierre-Laurent Buyrette), 1727-1775 (Box 17, Folder 218)
    - Belzoni, Giovanni Battista, 1778-1823 (Box 17, Folder 219)
    - Benbow, John, 1653?-1702 (Box 17, Folder 220)
    - Bentham, Jeremy, 1748-1832 (Box 17, Folder 221)
    - Benton, Thomas Hart, 1782-1858 (Box 17, Folder 222)
    - Béranger, Pierre Jean de, 1780-1857 (Box 18, Folder 223)
    - Beresford, William Carr, Viscount, 1768-1854 (Box 18, Folder 224)
    - Bergasse, Nicolas, 1750-1832 (Box 18, Folder 225)
    - Berkeley, George Berkeley, Earl of, 1628-1698 (Box 18, Folder 226)
    - Bernard, of Clairvaux, Saint, 1090 or 91-1153 (Box 18, Folder 227)
    - Bernhard, Duke of Saxe-Weimar, 1604-1639 (Box 18, Folder 228)
    - Berry, Charles, duc de, 1686-1714 (Box 18, Folder 229)
    - Berry, Charles-Ferdinand de Bourbon, duc de, 1778-1820 (Box 18, Folder 230)
    - Berry, Edward, Sir, 1768-1831 (Box 18, Folder 231)
    - Berry, Marie-Caroline de Bourbon-Sicile, duchesse de, 1798-1870 (Box 18, Folder 232)
    - Berthier, Louis-Alexandre, 1753-1815 (Box 18, Folder 233)
    - Bertrand, Henri-Gratien, comte, 1773-1844 (Box 18, Folder 234)
    - Berwick, James Fitzjames, Duke of, 1670-1734 (Box 18, Folder 235)
    - Besenval, Pierre-Victor, baron de, 1721-1791 (Box 18, Folder 236)
    - Bessieres, Jean-Baptiste, duc d'Istria (Box 18, Folder 237)
    - Betterton, Thomas, 1635?-1710 (Box 18, Folder 238)
    - Betty, William Hen. West (William Henry West), 1791-1874 (Box 18, Folder 239)
    - Beurnonville, Pierre Riel, marquis de, 1752-1821 (Box 18, Folder 240)
    - Beveridge, William, 1637-1708 (Box 18, Folder 241)
    - Bickersteth (Box 18, Folder 242)
    - Biron (Box 18, Folder 243)
    - Biron, Charles de Gontaut, duc de, 1562-1602 (Box 18, Folder 244)
    - Bishop, Samuel, 1731-1795 (Box 18, Folder 245)
    - Bismark, Otto, Furst von (Box 18, Folder 246)
    - Black, William, 1841-1898 (Box 18, Folder 247)
    - Blake, Robert, 1599-1657 (Box 18, Folder 248)
    - Blanc, Louis, 1811-1882 (Box 18, Folder 249)
    - Blessington, Marguerite, Countess of, 1789-1849 (Box 18, Folder 250)
    - Blood, Thomas, 1618?-1680 (Box 19, Folder 251)
    - Bloomfield, Robert, 1766-1823 (Box 19, Folder 252)
    - Blücher, Gebhard Leberecht von, 1742-1819 (Box 19, Folder 253)
    - Boccaccio, Giovanni, 1313-1375 (Box 19, Folder 254)
    - Bodley, Thomas, Sir, 1545-1613 (Box 19, Folder 255)
    - Boigne, Benoît Le Borgne, comte de, 1741-1830 (Box 19, Folder 256)
    - Boileau Despréaux, Nicolas, 1636-1711 (Box 19, Folder 257)
    - Boissard, Jean Jacques, 1528-1602 (Box 19, Folder 258)
    - Boissy d'Anglas, François-Antoine, comte de, 1756-1826 (Box 19, Folder 259)
    - Bolingbroke, Henry St. John, Viscount, 1678-1751 (Box 19, Folder 260)
    - Bolívar, Simón, 1783-1830 (Box 19, Folder 261)
    - Bonchamps, Charles-Melchior-Artus, marquis de, 1760-1793 (Box 19, Folder 262)
    - Bonnier d'Alco, Ange Elisabeth Louis Antonin, 1750-1799 (Box 19, Folder 263)
    - Boone, Daniel, 1734-1820 (Box 19, Folder 264)
    - Booth, Edwin, 1833-1893 (Box 19, Folder 265)
    - Booth, John Wilkes, 1838-1865 (Box 19, Folder 266)
    - Borgia, Cesare, 1476?-1507 (Box 19, Folder 267)
    - Boscawen, Edward, 1711-1761 (Box 19, Folder 268)
    - Bossuet, Jacques Bénigne, 1627-1704 (Box 19, Folder 269)
    - Botta, Carlo, 1766-1837 (Box 19, Folder 270)
    - Boucicaut, ca. 1366-1421 (Box 19, Folder 271)
    - Bouillon (Box 19, Folder 272)
    - Bouillon, Godefroy de, ca. 1060-1100 (Box 19, Folder 273)
    - Bouquet, Henry, 1719-1765 (Box 19, Folder 274)
    - Bourbon, Louis Jean-Marie de, duc de Penthièvre, 1725-1793 (Box 19, Folder 275)
    - Bourdaloue, Louis, 1632-1704 (Box 19, Folder 276)
    - Bourmont, Louis-Auguste-Victor de Ghaisne, comte de, 1773-1846 (Box 19, Folder 277)
    - Bracciolini, Poggio, 1380-1459 (Box 20, Folder 278)
    - Bradford, John, 1510?-1555 (Box 20, Folder 279)
    - Bradford, William, 1663-1752 (Box 20, Folder 280)
    - Bradshaw, John, 1602-1659 (Box 20, Folder 281)
    - Brandenburg (Box 20, Folder 282)
    - Brantôme, Pierre de Bourdeille, seigneur de, d. 1614 (Box 20, Folder 283)
    - Brathwaite, Richard, 1588?-1673 (Box 20, Folder 284)
    - Brederode (Box 20, Folder 285)
    - Brewster, David, Sir, 1781-1868 (Box 20, Folder 286)
    - Bright, John, 1811-1889 (Box 20, Folder 287)
    - Brissac (Box 20, Folder 288)
    - Brissac, Charles I de Cosse, comte de (Box 20, Folder 289)
    - Brissot de Warville, J.-P. (Jacques-Pierre), 1754-1793 (Box 20, Folder 290)
    - Bristol, John Digby, Earl of, 1580-1654 (Box 20, Folder 291)
    - Broglie (Box 20)
    - Brooke, Robert Greville, Baron, 1607-1643 (Box 20, Folder 292)
    - Brougham and Vaux, Henry Brougham, Baron, 1778-1868 (Box 20, Folder 293)
    - Broussel, Pierre (Box 20, Folder 294)
    - Brown (Box 20, Folder 295)
    - Browne (Box 20, Folder 296)
    - Brownrig, Ralph, 1592-1659 (Box 20, Folder 297)
    - Brune, Guillaume-Marie-Anne, 1763-1815 (Box 20, Folder 298)
    - Bryant, William Cullen, 1794-1878 (Box 20, Folder 299)
    - Brydges, Egerton, Sir, 1762-1837 (Box 20, Folder 300)
    - Buchanan, George, 1506-1582 (Box 20, Folder 301)
    - Buchanan, James, 1791-1868 (Box 20, Folder 302)
    - Buckingham (Box 21, Folder 303)
    - Buckingham, George Villiers, Duke of, 1592-1628 (Box 21, Folder 304)
    - Buckingham, George Villiers, Duke of, 1628-1687 (Box 21, Folder 305)
    - Buckingham, John Sheffield, Duke of, 1648-1720 or 21 (Box 21, Folder 306)
    - Bucquoi, Karl Bonaventura von Longueval, Graf von, 1571-1621 (Box 21, Folder 307)
    - Budé, Guillaume, 1468-1540 (Box 21, Folder 308)
    - Bülow, Friedrich Wilhelm, Freiherr von, 1755-1816 (Box 21, Folder 309)
    - Bunyan, John, 1628-1688 (Box 21, Folder 310)
    - Burdett, Francis, Sir, 1770-1844 (Box 21, Folder 311)
    - Bürger, Gottfried August, 1747-1794 (Box 21, Folder 312)
    - Burghley, William Cecil, Baron, 1520-1598 (Box 21, Folder 313)
    - Burgoyne, John, 1739-1785 (Box 21, Folder 314)
    - Burgundy (Box 21, Folder 315)
    - Burke, Edmund, 1729-1797 (Box 21, Folder 316)
    - Burnet, Gilbert, 1643-1715 (Box 21, Folder 317)
    - Burns, Robert, 1759-1796 (Box 21, Folder 318)
    - Burnside, Ambrose Everett, 1824-1881 (Box 21, Folder 319)
    - Burr, Aaron, 1756-1836 (Box 21, Folder 320)
    - Burton, Robert, 1577-1640 (Box 22, Folder 321)
    - Burton, William, 1575-1645 (Box 22, Folder 322)
    - Burton, William E. (William Evans), 1802-1860 (Box 22, Folder 323)
    - Bussy, Roger de Rabutin, comte de, 1618-1693 (Box 22, Folder 324)
    - Bute, John Stuart, Earl of, 1713-1792 (Box 22, Folder 325)
    - Butler, Benjamin F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1818-1893 (Box 22, Folder 326)
    - Butler, Pierce, 1744-1822 (Box 22, Folder 327)
    - Butler, Samuel, 1612-1680 (Box 22, Folder 328)
    - Buxton, Thomas Fowell, Sir, 1786-1845 (Box 22, Folder 329)
    - Buzot, François, 1760-1794 (Box 22, Folder 330)
    - Byron, George Gordon Byron, Baron, 1788-1824, 3 (Box 22, Folder 331-333)
    - Byron, John, 1723-1786 (Box 22, Folder 334)
    - Oversize
      - Ba - Ben general, 17 (Box 23 (Oversize), Folder 335-351)
      - Ber - Bl general, 10 (Box 24 (Oversize), Folder 352-361)
      - Bo - Bri general, 9 (Box 25 (Oversize), Folder 362-370)
      - Bro - Bz general, 8 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 371-378)
      - Baden - Belzoni, 34 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 379-412)
      - Benbow - Blücher, 31 (Box 28 (Oversize), Folder 413-443)
      - Boccaccio - Broglie, 28 (Box 29 (Oversize), Folder 444-471)
      - Brooke - Bussy, 23 (Box 30 (Oversize), Folder 472-494)
      - Bute - Byron, 7 (Box 31 (Oversize), Folder 495-501)
  - C
    - Ca - Carr general, 11 (Box 32, Folder 502-512)
    - Cars - Chap general, 12 (Box 33, Folder 513-524)
    - Char - Ci general, 11 (Box 34, Folder 525-535)
    - Cla - Conc general, 12 (Box 35, Folder 536-547)